http://www.lsuagcenter.com/sitecore/content/lsuagcenter/portals/utilities/footer/privacy

Search
.
Viewer Privacy
This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for lsuagcenter.com, a website of the Louisiana State University Agricultural Center (LSU AgCenter).
1. Information Collection and Use
The LSU AgCenter is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. The LSU AgCenter collects information from our users at several different points on our website.
1.1 Automatic Collection
If a user has not taken specific steps to anonymize their personal web traffic (e.g. apply mechanisms such as the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on that disable the collection of data for analytical purposes), official LSU AgCenter websites may collect certain information automatically. This information includes, but is not limited to:
User’s Internet protocol (IP) address
Internet service provider
Operating system
The time and date of the visit
Browser
The site from which the user visited
Cookie information (if applicable)
Any information collected automatically is not associated with any other information held by the LSU AgCenter (i.e. not linked with information voluntarily provided to the LSU AgCenter) unless the LSU Ag Center is required to do so by law.
1.2 Use
Website information that is gathered automatically is utilized to improve the understanding of how the LSU AgCenter websites are being leveraged by the user community. For example, the LSU AgCenter uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses “cookies” (i.e. files used to track website activity) to determine how users navigate the LSU AgCenter site. Google uses this cookie data for various purposes, including the evaluation of website use, reports on website activity, and other services. Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics’ terms of use and Google’s privacy practices.
Our "Get It Growing" video player makes use of the YouTube API Services. Please visit the following pages for more information on YouTube's terms of service and privacy policy.
Any information submitted to the LSU AgCenter voluntarily in order to receive services and/or information will only be utilized to conduct official university business. the LSU AgCenter may disseminate voluntarily submitted information to third parties and offices/departments within the LSU AgCenter to the extent necessary in order to provide the requested services and/or information. the LSU AgCenter may also disseminate such information if required by applicable law-enforcement agencies.
The LSU AgCenter will not disclose any information submitted voluntarily for reasons other than mentioned above, without clear notice and the opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such uses. The LSU AgCenter will never sell or trade voluntarily submitted information to other entities unless a prior consent has been obtained and/or such information is being shared in response to a subpoena, court order, or legal process.
There is no legal requirement for a user to provide any information to the LSU AgCenter. However, without certain information, the LSU AgCenter websites and services may not function as intended and features may be inaccessible
2. Registration
In order to use certain areas of this website, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as social security number), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.
3. Order
We may request information from the user on some order forms. Here a user may provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.
4. Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
5. Log Files
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
6. Links
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, The LSU AgCenter, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.
7. Newsletter
If a user wishes to subscribe to one of our newsletters, we ask for contact information such as name and email address.
8. Surveys
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.
9. Referrals
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. The LSU AgCenter will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. The LSU AgCenter stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact The LSU AgCenter by e-mail at web@agcenter.lsu.edu to request the removal of this information from their database.
10. Security
This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’.
11. Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.
Rate This Article:
Rating
×
Thank you!
Your rating has been submitted.
Close
Have a question or comment about the information on this page?
Click here to contact us.
